How's it going everyone? In this video,
I will be doing a trade review over a
trade I took on CAD futures. Now, we
will start with a dollar analysis. I'll
show how I use that dollar analysis to
trade CAD futures and then we'll also
end with how you could trade this on USD
CAD. So the first thing I want you to
notice on dollar here is we have a
bearish candle 2 closure on the monthly
time frame. So that is telling me that I
am bearish on this monthly candle.
Really I'm looking at this and asking is
price more likely to reach for its
previous month's high or its previous
month's low considering we are closer to
previous month's low. I'm just looking
for that previous month's low to taken
out. And it also helps we have equal
lows right here. So just to add to that
context, we have taken out this high. We
have expansion into the high met with
expansion out. So blending with those
phases of price. This is a reversal. Now
right here, do we get a new phase of
price? We get a retracement, right? It
doesn't expand back higher to make a
higher low and make a new higher high.
It is a retracement. So then we continue
lower. And so I really don't want to see
this high taken out as we continue to
trade lower because we'd have a high, a
lower high. I want to see a new lower
high and a new lower low. So with that,
we have opposing candle here. I want to
see that being respected. And we have a
candle to closure. So now I have
everything lined up here on the dollar.
I have a higher time frame drawn
liquidity where I'm looking for the
daily chart to trade into these lows. I
have a candle 2 closure on the daily.
Now the last thing I can do is go down
to the hourly chart and confirm that we
have a change in the state of delivery
in this candle too. If you notice, we do
as price reaches higher and trades
lower. And if you focus on the bodies
here, we have a nice V-shaped reversal
to add to that candle to closure. Now
that I have a bearish bias for dollar,
that gives me a bullish bias for foreign
currencies. I'm going to want to take a
look at these foreign currencies or the
currency futures and find a chart that I
like. So you see here, we could trade
euro into this high that is valid. We
could also take a look at pound with
this candle to closure and trading it
higher. Now, as I scrolled through
these, the one that caught my eye was
Canadian futures, and that is because of
how it has this daily formation. So, if
you notice, it also took out this low
here. It has a nice V-shaped reversal.
Price opens, trades into this fair value
gap, and then has a candle to closure.
Now, what's specific about this candle
to closure? It is an ideal candle to
closure. It also forms a protected swing
here. So now I can look for this next
day in candle 3 to trade higher. Where
would I want to see this trade into?
Previous month's high and then also our
previous month's high. And you can see
we have a nice equal highs up here above
if we wanted to take swing targets. So
from the daily I drop down to the hourly
to check for the structure. So letting
this play ahead. My indicator went and
marked out this level. And what I'll do
is I'll keep this drawing on the daily
chart here. So one thing I want to say
is I want to see this daily opposing
candle be respected. So what do I mean
by that? I can mark out 0.5. I want to
see the wick of this next candle formed
in the upper half of this area as well
as the upper half of this daily candle.
So I know if I move this over here, I
want to see the wick formed in this area
which is in that T-spot. So I know I
want to see price trade higher. What is
my next step? I want to look for
protected swings. You can see I have one
here as price reaches into a fair value
gap and closes over. So what does that
do? That protects this low right here.
So I have an invalidation if I wanted to
take an entry. But what else do I have?
I have a new invalidation because we
have a new protected swing. Price
reaches into this fair value gap and
then closes over. So now what do I have?
I have price opening up right near an
invalidation. So, I could look to take a
positional entry into this overnight and
let this swing into the next day or into
the morning to see if it works out or
not. Now, letting this play, where did I
get on side on this trade? Well, I saw
price respect this right here. So, I
went ahead and took an entry right here,
put my stop on the protected low, and
then I was looking for price to trade
into this high here. Now, let's see how
this worked out overnight.
So, here we are into the New York
session. This is when I woke up and what
are we at? We're at over 2 R. I was
looking to take some partials off here,
but what did I noticed? We have three
candles of expansion. This is when we
can get a new phase of price. I went and
looked at the 30inut chart here and I
saw that price was consolidating. So,
what I did was I just set a TP at this
high cuz if we have a consolidation and
price takes the high, that's when we can
get a new phase of price and reverse.
So, letting this play out, I took a TP
right here. So, I entered right in this
candle here and exited in this candle
here. As you can see on the screen and I
just exited there with right around 2.3
R. As you let this play out, you can see
it was a pretty good exit. Now, if we
zoom back out to the daily chart, if I
would have swung this trade, it would
have worked out well, but it was a day
trade for me. I was just trading the
daily range of this daily candle here,
which I did rather well. But if I did
want to swing it, this is why it's
important to align your time frames is
you do get this really nice move higher
here as we get an expansion on the
monthly candle and you're trading that
expansion. If I go back to the hourly
chart here, you can see how that area
for my entry was respected and then we
do get that breakout of the range or
that expansion. So now what if you
wanted to trade this same thing but on
USD CAD? Well, you have the same idea,
but it's going to be the other way.
Since you are bearish on dollar and it
is USD CAD, not CAD USD, it's going to
be a bearish setup. So, going to USD
CAD, it would be the exact same idea.
Here we have the candle to closure.
We're looking for this to trade lower.
And then once again, I'm just looking
for those protected swings. Here you can
see I have a protected swing. And here
we have another protected swing reaching
into a fair value gap and then closing
below. So price opening up right into an
order block. I can look to take that
same entry but my same stop loss and do
I get 2 R? Right. Well, if I approach it
the exact same way. I'd get essentially
the exact same results. Now if I let
that continue to play out, it would also
get that expansion because if we go back
to the daily chart, what is it? It's
that daily and monthly expansion candle
that we go and trade into those lows and
those targets below. Now, just because I
chose to trade this on USD CAD or CAD
futures doesn't mean that you couldn't
use the same setup on a different asset.
For example, if you went ahead and
traded this on GBPUSD,
you had a way better expansion on that
day. So, I actually did not choose the
strongest asset that day. I chose the
strongest asset over the next few days,
but I could have done better and traded
GBPUSD here. If we go to the hourly
chart, you'll see what I mean. That same
time I entered CAD futures right here,
we get this massive expansion on GBPUSD.
That being said, the structure was a bit
better for me on CAD futures than it was
on GBPUSD, but GBPUSD actually had the
more expansive move. Now, with that, I
hope you enjoyed this video. If you have
any questions, let me know in the
comments section below and I'll get to
them. I hope you have a great rest of
your day and I'll see you guys next
time.